<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hail the Octopus.</title>
    <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/</link>
    <description>Hi! I am Adrika, a second year undergrad at IISER Kolkata. I like long hikes, birdwatching, reading, and cooking. Have a nice day!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thepiedpieper.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The Streaked Spiderhunter</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/birds/streaked-spiderhunter/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/birds/streaked-spiderhunter/</guid>
        <description>The Streaked Spiderhunter If you are ever out birding in montane forests in eastern India, and if you are lucky enough to see scores of small birds flitting about in the trees on dainty wings, you can always spot these birds out by their obscenely long beaks.
There are eleven species of spiderhunters in South and Southeastern Asia, and this is one of the two found in India.
Spiderhunters forage all parts of the forest canopy, never veering close to the ground; if you stand long enough, they appear almost squirrel-like as they scuttle and look for small invertebrates.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sex Peptide in Drosophila melanogaster</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/drosophila/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/drosophila/</guid>
        <description>The Sex Peptide in Drosophila melanogaster melSP is a component of the seminal fluid that induces post mating responses in Drosophila females. It is gradually released by proteolytic cleavage and induces several long-term postmating responses What does this entail? SP acts on internal sensory neurons expressing pickpocket(ppk). These then induce PMR.
Classic Post Mating responses elevated egg-laying
reluctance to further mating
altered dietary preference(high protein:carbohydrate interference) - (testing nutrient deficient flies by activating this group of neurons?</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Black Headed Ibis</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/birds/the-black-headed-ibis/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/birds/the-black-headed-ibis/</guid>
        <description>The Black Headed Ibis (Threskiornins melanocephalus), also known as the Oriental white ibis, is a large wader found over a large range of South-eastern Asia. It is a large Ciconiiform (order comprising storklike birds) with adults measuring 65-70cm.
It is the only native ibis species in its range that has an overall white plumage with a black neck and head. The down-curved beak and legs are also black.
Introduction
The black headed ibis is a medium, nomadic, wading waterbird, frequently found in association with other Ciconiiforms or pelicaniiforms in shallow waters.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Plains Cupid</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/butterflies/the-plains-cupid/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/butterflies/the-plains-cupid/</guid>
        <description>Subject - The Plains Cupid (Luthrodes pandava)
Long afternoon walks are the best thing to happen to raccoon-eyed college students who have taken to living in the library. Especially if you are intercepted by these pretty sights; they flit about in the bushes, and dance nimbly on the slender stalks of coatbuttons, and overall, make a torrid summer more bearable.
A male wet season brood
These butterflies belong to the Lycaenidae family (tribe Polyommatini) of butterflies, (the second-largest family of butterflies behind Nymphalidae, or the brush footed butterflies), whose members are called gossamer-winged butterflies.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chapter 2 - Principles of Neural Science</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/neurobiology/chapter-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 09:32:56 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/neurobiology/chapter-2/</guid>
        <description>Chapter 2 Principles of Neural Science Synaptic Plasticity and localisation of mRNA translation in axons Nuerobiology Glial Cells Functions: Nourishment to neurons Structure Dev &amp;mdash; migration cues by radial glia Myelin Sheath Blood Brain Barrier Scavengers Signalling Pre-synaptic terminal control Types: Microglia Immune cells arising from macrophages, embryologically and physiologically diff from other merve cells Unknown rest conditions, stouter process when activated after injury Produce antigens, active in MS and AIDS-related dementia Macroglia Oligodendrocytes and Schwann cells Provide insulation through myelin sheath not very branched, myelin by each differes in chemical composition Astrocytes Not very processed Has end feet Brings nutrients Blood-brain barrier Maintains K-ion conc.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Border Cell Migration</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/dev-bio/border-cell-migration/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 09:32:56 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/dev-bio/border-cell-migration/</guid>
        <description>What is migration? The conversion of stationary epithelial cells into migratory, invasive cells, which is important for normal embryonic development. How do cells achieve this? Cells that are part of a stable epithelium lose their cell-cell and cell-matrix junctions that hold them together and acquire a less rigidly polarised morphology and break away from their neighbours.
Forward genetic analysis This involves uncovering the genetic basis behind a particular phenotype. Mutant lines are screened for specific defects in the process of interest.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chapter 4 - Neural Science</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/neurobiology/chapter-4/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/neurobiology/chapter-4/</guid>
        <description>deals with degree of localisation in brain
explanaing behaviour as properties of specific nerve cells and interconnections in particular regions of brain
Talks about how neurons are different because of polarisation, excitability, and molecules they produce, along with compartmentalisation which helps in effective and quick conduction of signals
Neurons similar to epithelial cells neurons develop from epithelium basolateral surface ‒ cyton part with dendrite &amp;amp; apical surface - part from which axon arises plasmalemma with asymmetric bilayer, same cytosolic housekeeping proteins; extra is some special ones, like ones used to degrade neurotransmitters Selective distribution of organelles and molecules throughout cell Vesicular pathways - exocytic (membrane proteins secreted by RER - Golgi incorporated into plasmalemma, secretory pathway) &amp;amp; endocytic (membrane taken in from plasmalemma shuttled back by vesicular recycling, or taken to lysosomes for degradation by endosomes) Shape of neuron determined by cytoskeleton cytoskeleton - microtubules, neuronal filaments, actin microtubules - made of tubulin (GTPase); poylmerisation happens due to binding of GTP bound tubulin dimers.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chapter 5 - Neural Science</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/neurobiology/chapter-5/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/neurobiology/chapter-5/</guid>
        <description>Synthesis and Transport of Neuronal Protein Protein Synthesis in the Cell Body mostly in cell body and dendrite beginnings different sequences in N-terminal or inside mark it for different processes, for example, modification, secretion, or say degradation(Ubiquitinylation) chaperons(Hsp70) help in protein folding (energy dependent) Protein Modification changes - cotranslational/ posttranslational permanent/transient N-acylation (Myristoylation) - addition of lipid chain to acylated N-terminus(Gly) allow it to associate with membrane through chain Thioacylation - allow protein to associate with cytosolic leaflet of membrane (e.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basics</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/dnarep/basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/dnarep/basics/</guid>
        <description>DNA Watson and Crick&amp;rsquo;s hypothesis had immediately suggested a possible self-replication method for DNA because of complementarity in base pairing.
At this junction, possible modes of DNA replication: Conservative / Semi-conservative / Dispersive
Meselson-Stahl Experiment proves replication is semi-conservative Bacteria grown in N(15) medium incorporate N14 in a light medium - CsCl density gradient centrifugation revealed.
Identification of Replication Fork John Cairns identified the replication fork by allowing replicating DNA in cells to incorporate tritiated thymidine.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/week-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/week-1/</guid>
        <description>Introduction </description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Regulation of DNA replication</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/dnarep/regulation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/dnarep/regulation/</guid>
        <description>Regulation Q. Why don&#39;t somatic cells have telomerases? They prevent the accummulation of harmful mutations in this way.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RNAs</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/rna/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/molgen/rna/</guid>
        <description>RNA </description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>