<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hail the Octopus.</title>
    <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/tags/insects/</link>
    <description>Hi! I am Adrika, a second year undergrad at IISER Kolkata. I like long hikes, birdwatching, reading, and cooking. Have a nice day!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thepiedpieper.github.io/tags/insects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Sex Peptide in Drosophila melanogaster</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/drosophila/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/drosophila/</guid>
        <description>The Sex Peptide in Drosophila melanogaster melSP is a component of the seminal fluid that induces post mating responses in Drosophila females. It is gradually released by proteolytic cleavage and induces several long-term postmating responses What does this entail? SP acts on internal sensory neurons expressing pickpocket(ppk). These then induce PMR.
Classic Post Mating responses elevated egg-laying
reluctance to further mating
altered dietary preference(high protein:carbohydrate interference) - (testing nutrient deficient flies by activating this group of neurons?</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Plains Cupid</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/butterflies/the-plains-cupid/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/butterflies/the-plains-cupid/</guid>
        <description>Subject - The Plains Cupid (Luthrodes pandava)
Long afternoon walks are the best thing to happen to raccoon-eyed college students who have taken to living in the library. Especially if you are intercepted by these pretty sights; they flit about in the bushes, and dance nimbly on the slender stalks of coatbuttons, and overall, make a torrid summer more bearable.
A male wet season brood
These butterflies belong to the Lycaenidae family (tribe Polyommatini) of butterflies, (the second-largest family of butterflies behind Nymphalidae, or the brush footed butterflies), whose members are called gossamer-winged butterflies.</description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>