<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hail the Octopus.</title>
    <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/tags/biology/</link>
    <description>Hi! I am Adrika, a second year undergrad at IISER Kolkata. I like long hikes, birdwatching, reading, and cooking. Have a nice day!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thepiedpieper.github.io/tags/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Sex Peptide in Drosophila melanogaster</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/drosophila/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/insects/drosophila/</guid>
        <description>The Sex Peptide in Drosophila melanogaster melSP is a component of the seminal fluid that induces post mating responses in Drosophila females. It is gradually released by proteolytic cleavage and induces several long-term postmating responses What does this entail? SP acts on internal sensory neurons expressing pickpocket(ppk). These then induce PMR.
Classic Post Mating responses elevated egg-laying
reluctance to further mating
altered dietary preference(high protein:carbohydrate interference) - (testing nutrient deficient flies by activating this group of neurons?</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Border Cell Migration</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/dev-bio/border-cell-migration/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 09:32:56 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/biology/dev-bio/border-cell-migration/</guid>
        <description>What is migration? The conversion of stationary epithelial cells into migratory, invasive cells, which is important for normal embryonic development. How do cells achieve this? Cells that are part of a stable epithelium lose their cell-cell and cell-matrix junctions that hold them together and acquire a less rigidly polarised morphology and break away from their neighbours.
Forward genetic analysis This involves uncovering the genetic basis behind a particular phenotype. Mutant lines are screened for specific defects in the process of interest.</description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>