<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi!</title>
    <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Hi! I am Adrika, a second year undergrad at IISER Kolkata. I like long hikes, birdwatching, reading, and cooking. Have a nice day!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 09:32:56 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thepiedpieper.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Border Cell Migration</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/posts/dev-bio/border-cell-migration/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 09:32:56 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/posts/dev-bio/border-cell-migration/</guid>
        <description>What is migration? The conversion of stationary epithelial cells into migratory, invasive cells, which is important for normal embryonic development. How do cells achieve this? Cells that are part of a stable epithelium lose their cell-cell and cell-matrix junctions that hold them together and acquire a less rigidly polarised morphology and break away from their neighbours.
Forward genetic analysis This involves uncovering the genetic basis behind a particular phenotype. Mutant lines are screened for specific defects in the process of interest.</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Plains Cupid</title>
        <link>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/posts/insects/butterflies/the-plains-cupid/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 09:19:01 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://thepiedpieper.github.io/posts/insects/butterflies/the-plains-cupid/</guid>
        <description>Subject - The Plains Cupid (Luthrodes pandava)
Long afternoon walks are the best thing to happen to raccoon-eyed college students who have taken to living in the library. Especially if you are intercepted by these pretty sights; they flit about in the bushes, and dance nimbly on the slender stalks of coatbuttons, and overall, make a torrid summer more bearable.
A male wet season brood
These butterflies belong to the Lycaenidae family (tribe Polyommatini) of butterflies, (the second-largest family of butterflies behind Nymphalidae, or the brush footed butterflies), whose members are called gossamer-winged butterflies.</description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>